[
    {
        "id":1,
        "question":"Which of the following command is used to create react-js-app ?",
        "options":["npx create-react-app appname","npm install create-react-app","npx install create-react-app -g","install - l create-react-app"],
        "correctOption":"npx create-react-app appname"
    },
    {
        "id":2,
        "question":"In React.js which one of the following is used to create a class for Inheritance ?",
        "options":["Create","Extends","Inherits","Delete"],
        "correctOption":"Extends"
    },
    {
        "id":3,
        "question":"What is the default port number in which the application run ?",
        "options":["3000","8080","5000","3030"],
        "correctOption":"3000"
    },
    {
        "id":4,
        "question":"Which of the following is a way to handle data in React.js ?",
        "options":["State & Props","Services & Components","State & Services","State & Component"],
        "correctOption":"State & Props"
    },
    {
        "id":5,
        "question":"Which of the following is must for the API in React.js ?",
        "options":["SetinitialComponent","renderComponent","render","All of the above"],
        "correctOption":"renderComponent"
    },
    {
        "id":6,
        "question":"Which of the following is true regarding Babel ?",
        "options":["Compiler","Transpilar","Both of the above","None of the above"],
        "correctOption":"Both of the above"
    },
    {
        "id":7,
        "question":"In React.js, how we can pass the data from one component to another in React.js ?",
        "options":["SetState","Render with Arguments","Props","PropTypes"],
        "correctOption":"Props"
    },
    {
        "id":8,
        "question":"Which of the following function is true about changing the state in React.js ?",
        "options":["this.State{}","this.setState","this.setChangeState","All of the above"],
        "correctOption":"this.setState"
    },
    {
        "id":9,
        "question":"Which of the following method is true about referring parent class in React.js ?",
        "options":["self()","inherits()","this()","super()"],
        "correctOption":"super()"
    },
    {
        "id":10,
        "question":"Which of the following is used to render components in web pages ?",
        "options":["DOM-render()","render()","ReactDOM_render()","transfer()"],
        "correctOption":"render()"
    }
]